{
  "introduction": null,
  "language_2": "th",
  "name": "Thai",
  "language_1": "en",
  "voice_1": null,
  "pul_elements": [
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nee↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "this",
      "answer": "นี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "film, movie",
      "answer": "หนัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[duu→], ดูหนังนี้ [duu→ nang↗ nee↑] : Watch this movie."
        }
      ],
      "question": "to look at, to watch",
      "answer": "ดู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to go",
      "answer": "ไป"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[si↑], ไปซิ [bpai→ si↑] : Let's go!, ดูนี่ซิ [duu→ nee↘ si↑] : Look here!"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a particle which conveys urgency, adding an imperative quality)",
      "answer": "ซิ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohm↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(used by male speakers) I, me",
      "answer": "ผม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gin→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to eat or drink",
      "answer": "กิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naam↑], ผมกินน้ำ. [phohm↗ gin→ naam↑] : I drink water."
        }
      ],
      "question": "water, liquid",
      "answer": "น้ำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaawp↘], ผมชอบกินน้ำ. [phohm↗ chaawp↘ gin→ naam↑] : I like to drink water."
        }
      ],
      "question": "to like",
      "answer": "ชอบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yen→], ผมชอบกินน้ำเย็น. [phohm↗ chaawp↘ gin→ naam↑ yen→] : I like to drink cold water."
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of an object) (is) cold",
      "answer": "เย็น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheuu↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "name",
      "answer": "ชื่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[a↓ rai→], ชื่ออะไร [cheuu↘ a↓ rai→] : What is your name."
        }
      ],
      "question": "(indicating a question) what",
      "answer": "อะไร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khoon→], คุณชอบกินอะไร [khoon→ chaawp↘ gin→ a↓ rai→] : What do you like to drink ?"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(singular and plural) you",
      "answer": "คุณ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawp↓], ขอบคุณ [khaawp↓ khoon→] : Thank you."
        }
      ],
      "question": "pertaining to thanks",
      "answer": "ขอบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maak↘], ขอบคุณมาก [khaawp↓ khoon→ maak↘] : Thanks a lot."
        }
      ],
      "question": "very",
      "answer": "มาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "day",
      "answer": "วัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wan→ nee↑], (Notice this + day = today.)"
        }
      ],
      "question": "today",
      "answer": "วันนี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaeng↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) hard, strong",
      "answer": "แข็ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nam↑ khaeng↗], (Notice hard + water = ice.)"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ice",
      "answer": "น้ำแข็ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ao→], ผมเอาน้ำแข็ง [phohm↗ ao→ nam↑ khaeng↗] : I want ice."
        }
      ],
      "question": "to want, to specify or order",
      "answer": "เอา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[an→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "thing, item",
      "answer": "อัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[an→ nee↑], เอาอันนี้. [ao→ an→ nee↑] : I want this one."
        }
      ],
      "question": "this thing",
      "answer": "อันนี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neung↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "one",
      "answer": "หนึ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[eek↓], อีกอันหนึ่ง. [eek↓ an→ neung↓] : Another one of these."
        }
      ],
      "question": "again, still",
      "answer": "อีก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khuaat↓], ขวดน้ำ [khuaat↓ naam↑] : a bottle of water"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bottle",
      "answer": "ขวด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maae↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "mother",
      "answer": "แม่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maae↘ naam↑], (Notice mother + water = river.)"
        }
      ],
      "question": "river",
      "answer": "แม่น้ำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaao↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "foot",
      "answer": "เท้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[groong→ thaehp↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bangkok",
      "answer": "กรุงเทพฯ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khlaawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of water) a canal",
      "answer": "คลอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to support (from below), to place (something) under",
      "answer": "รอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng→ thaao↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "shoe or shoes, footwear, boot or boots",
      "answer": "รองเท้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "beach",
      "answer": "หาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deern→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to walk",
      "answer": "เดิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dek↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "child",
      "answer": "เด็ก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wing↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to run",
      "answer": "วิ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→ mai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "why",
      "answer": "ทำไม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raaeng→], คุณแข็งแรง"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) strong, powerful, energetic, having energy, hard",
      "answer": "แรง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cha↓ laat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) smart, intelligent, clever",
      "answer": "ฉลาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chim→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to taste",
      "answer": "ชิม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaak↓ gaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "pen",
      "answer": "ปากกา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meet↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "knife",
      "answer": "มีด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawm↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fork",
      "answer": "ส้อม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaawn↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "spoon",
      "answer": "ช้อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohm↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) orange, citrus, orange color",
      "answer": "ส้ม"
    },
    {
      "answer": "รู้สึก",
      "question": "to feel"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a trace, a mark",
      "answer": "รอย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawy→ sak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a tatoo",
      "answer": "รอยสัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to give",
      "answer": "ให้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luuk↘ khaa↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "customer",
      "answer": "ลูกค้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aat↓ ja↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "maybe, possibly",
      "answer": "อาจจะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nuu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "pronoun for kids, servants",
      "answer": "หนู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to be named, called",
      "answer": "เรียก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraw↑ waa↘] difference with เพราะ ???"
        }
      ],
      "question": "because",
      "answer": "เพราะว่า"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ทั้งสองอย่าง",
      "question": "both"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtawng↘ gaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to need",
      "answer": "ต้องการ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaawp↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "reply",
      "answer": "ตอบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ra↑ biiang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "balcony",
      "answer": "ระเบียง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[feuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to train",
      "answer": "ฝึก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaang↓ ngaai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "simple",
      "answer": "อย่างง่าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wang↗ waa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to hope",
      "answer": "หวังว่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaang↓ ngaai↘ daai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "easily",
      "answer": "อย่างง่ายดาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lonely",
      "answer": "เหงา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jang→ wat↓] Thailand has 76 provinces"
        }
      ],
      "question": "province",
      "answer": "จังหวัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtam→ bohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "sub-district",
      "answer": "ตำบล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "word",
      "answer": "คำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kham→ sap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "vocabulary",
      "answer": "คำศัพท์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nak↑ thaawng↘ thiaao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "tourist",
      "answer": "นักท่องเที่ยว"
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลางวัน",
      "question": "day time"
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลางคืน",
      "question": "night time"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dta↓ leung→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "is stupefied",
      "answer": "ตะลึง"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ตัว",
      "question": "self"
    },
    {
      "answer": "กลิ่น",
      "question": "odor, smell"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ว่า",
      "question": "that"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ได้ยินมาว่า",
      "question": "i have heard that"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขี้อาย",
      "question": "to be shy"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ขำ",
      "question": "is amused, funny"
    },
    {
      "answer": "หัวเราะ",
      "question": "to laugh"
    },
    {
      "answer": "บันดาล",
      "question": "to inspire"
    },
    {
      "answer": "แรงบันดาลใจ",
      "question": "inspiration, muse"
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนังสือ",
      "question": "book"
    },
    {
      "answer": "หนังสือพิมพ์",
      "question": "newspaper"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ถูก",
      "question": "true, correct"
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิมพ์",
      "question": "to type"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ผิด",
      "question": "wrong, incorrect"
    },
    {
      "answer": "พิมพ์ผิด",
      "question": "to type wrong"
    },
    {
      "answer": "2อาทิตย์ต่อปี",
      "question": "2 weeks per year"
    },
    {
      "answer": "คุก",
      "question": "jail"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉิบหาย",
      "question": "damn!"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้น",
      "question": "tree"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ต้นสัก",
      "question": "teak tree"
    },
    {
      "answer": "บ้านนอก",
      "question": "countryside"
    },
    {
      "answer": "นาดำ",
      "question": "rice paddy"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "mouth or any part in the mouth",
      "answer": "ปาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohm↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hair (of the head)",
      "answer": "ผม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawy↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) little, small",
      "answer": "น้อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaw↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a particle or conjunction that emphasizes that which follows)",
      "answer": "ก็"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) sweet",
      "answer": "หวาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheep↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "life, existence, living",
      "answer": "ชีพ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) far, distant",
      "answer": "ไกล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) near, close",
      "answer": "ใกล้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) drunk, intoxicated",
      "answer": "เมา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaM thee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a minute",
      "answer": "นาที"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gee↓], กี่นาที : How many minutes ?"
        }
      ],
      "question": "how many",
      "answer": "กี่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "yes, I agree, correct, right, indeed, that's so",
      "answer": "ใช่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuum→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to forget",
      "answer": "ลืม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "milk, a woman's breast",
      "answer": "นม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[juup↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to kiss",
      "answer": "จูบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nohk↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bird",
      "answer": "นก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wat↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "temple, monastery",
      "answer": "วัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fish",
      "answer": "ปลา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[set↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) finished, completed, ready",
      "answer": "เสร็จ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaae↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "but, even, however, rather",
      "answer": "แต่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaang↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "elephant, pachyderm, Elephas maximus",
      "answer": "ช้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "in, inside, within, amidst, into, on, at a particular time",
      "answer": "ใน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to take, get, bring",
      "answer": "เอา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deuuan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "month",
      "answer": "เดือน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daaeng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) red",
      "answer": "แดง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheuun→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "night",
      "answer": "คืน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawy↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "often",
      "answer": "บ่อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gai↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "chicken",
      "answer": "ไก่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fohn↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "rain",
      "answer": "ฝน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuuan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "friend, pal, chum, buddy, older colleague",
      "answer": "เพื่อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reuu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "or",
      "answer": "หรือ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "can, to be able, is able, am able, may, might (auxiliary of potential, denoting possbility, ability, or permission)",
      "answer": "ได้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "we, us, our",
      "answer": "เรา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaa↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) slow",
      "answer": "ช้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haawng↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "room of a building, apartment, chamber",
      "answer": "ห้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suu↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to contend, fight, compete, make an aggressive move",
      "answer": "สู้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "not, no",
      "answer": "ไม่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yoong→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "mosquito",
      "answer": "ยุง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuuang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "city, nation, country, land, town",
      "answer": "เมือง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) black, dark, dusky",
      "answer": "ดำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lek↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) small, tiny, fine, little",
      "answer": "เล็ก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to come, <subject> comes",
      "answer": "มา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "rice",
      "answer": "ข้าว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ro:hngM riian→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) school (not used to refer to college or university)",
      "answer": "โรงเรียน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) heavy, laden, fully loaded, weighing",
      "answer": "หนัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laang↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to clean, wash, rinse",
      "answer": "ล้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaa↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "forest, woods, jungle, wild",
      "answer": "ป่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) white",
      "answer": "ขาว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[geert↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to be born, to birth, to happen",
      "answer": "เกิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "eye",
      "answer": "ตา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chen↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "similar to, same as",
      "answer": "เช่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[boon→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "holy, virtuous, pure, sacred",
      "answer": "บุญ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "yet, since, not yet, still",
      "answer": "ยัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to do or perform an action, to cause or effect a result",
      "answer": "ทำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohp↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to meet or rendezvous, locate, find, encounter, experience, discover",
      "answer": "พบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaaF mo:hng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(in time, of time) an hour (when used as a quantity)",
      "answer": "ชั่วโมง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phee↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "older sibling, older siblings",
      "answer": "พี่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "air, wind, storm, breeze",
      "answer": "ลม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to love, <subject> loves",
      "answer": "รัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaw→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "neck, throat",
      "answer": "คอ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) difficult, hard, not easy",
      "answer": "ยาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nakH riian→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "student, pupil (thru high school), schoolchildren",
      "answer": "นักเรียน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuu→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hand, hands",
      "answer": "มือ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngern→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "money, finance, silver",
      "answer": "เงิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "dog",
      "answer": "หมา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "head, mind",
      "answer": "เกล้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khruu→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "teacher, instructor",
      "answer": "ครู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cho:hk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "luck",
      "answer": "โชค"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[roht↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "car, vehicle, bus",
      "answer": "รถ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpit↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to close, turn off, to shut",
      "answer": "ปิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fire, flame",
      "answer": "ไฟ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "island",
      "answer": "เกาะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to think, consider, imagine, expect, compute, to count, wonder",
      "answer": "คิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpen→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to be, <subject> is",
      "answer": "เป็น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "drug, medicine, remedy, medication, having to do with medical treatment",
      "answer": "ยา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of geometric length) (is) long",
      "answer": "ยาว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawn↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of temperature) (is) hot",
      "answer": "ร้อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "long time, as time passes",
      "answer": "นาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "there (at a medium distance from here), those, that",
      "answer": "นั่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[muu↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Moo (part of a street address in Thailand), neighborhood, block",
      "answer": "หมู่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gwaa↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(suffix used for comparisons) than, more, -er",
      "answer": "กว่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaaek↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) strange, unusual, queer, weird, peculiar, odd, curious",
      "answer": "แปลก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuu↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to buy or purchase",
      "answer": "ซื้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM gaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "weather, air, climate",
      "answer": "อากาศ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khraawpF khruaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "family",
      "answer": "ครอบครัว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "male",
      "answer": "ชาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuM khao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hill, mountain",
      "answer": "ภูเขา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dto↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "table",
      "answer": "โต๊ะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuuan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) similar, all the same, like, as",
      "answer": "เหมือน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ga↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to, with, also",
      "answer": "กะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(used as a question) which, where, when",
      "answer": "ไหน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "news, tidings, information received, message",
      "answer": "ข่าว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nguu→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "snake",
      "answer": "งู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(indicating a condition) if",
      "answer": "ถ้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[niH yohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) popular",
      "answer": "นิยม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neuua↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "beef, flesh, tissue meat of any animal (especially) meat of the cow",
      "answer": "เนื้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(auxiliary verb) to want, desire, crave for",
      "answer": "อยาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raan↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "store or shop, commercial establishment, a place where merchandise is sold",
      "answer": "ร้าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaae↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a person or animal) (is) old, aged",
      "answer": "แก่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[namH man→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "oil, gasoline, fuel",
      "answer": "น้ำมัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "tooth",
      "answer": "ฟัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a human, chair, tripod, etc.) leg, lower extremities",
      "answer": "ขา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM saa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "language(s), speech, idiom, tongue, lingo, understanding, words",
      "answer": "ภาษา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a verb particle reflecting passive voice)",
      "answer": "ถูก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[miia→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "wife",
      "answer": "เมีย"
    },
    {
      "answer": "อวบ",
      "question": "chubby"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ro:hng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "building, hall, pavilion, structure, theater",
      "answer": "โรง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kha↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(word added by a female speaker to the end of every question to convey politeness)",
      "answer": "คะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naae↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) sure, certain, truthful, firm, stable, without doubt, exact",
      "answer": "แน่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to sell",
      "answer": "ขาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "work, job, duty, business, function",
      "answer": "งาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ying↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "female",
      "answer": "หญิง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "egg",
      "answer": "ไข่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaw↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "father",
      "answer": "พ่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reo→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) fast, quick, speedy",
      "answer": "เร็ว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Thai, of or pertaining to Thailand",
      "answer": "ไทย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to listen, listen to",
      "answer": "ฟัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) tiny, very small, microscopic",
      "answer": "นิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[uaan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) fat, overweight, not thin",
      "answer": "อ้วน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "with, to, for",
      "answer": "กับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaH laeh→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "sea",
      "answer": "ทะเล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nuu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "mouse, mice, rat",
      "answer": "หนู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaeng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) expensive",
      "answer": "แพง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luuk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "child, offspring, son or daughter (including figurative usage for certain ideas), cub, young animal",
      "answer": "ลูก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phee↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ghost, spirit",
      "answer": "ผี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) void, empty, naked, nothing",
      "answer": "เปล่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[diaao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) single, alone, sole",
      "answer": "เดี่ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fruit",
      "answer": "ผล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL duuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bone",
      "answer": "กระดูก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lae↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "and",
      "answer": "และ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riian→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to study at the elementary school level",
      "answer": "เรียน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[huaa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "head, brain, bulb, tuber",
      "answer": "หัว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaoF rai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "...how much?... how many?, to that extent",
      "answer": "เท่าไร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraw↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "because, because of, due to, owing to",
      "answer": "เพราะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suay↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) beautiful, pretty, lovely, gorgeous, attractive, nice-looking (usually referring to women but also possibly a view)",
      "answer": "สวย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaao↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "morning, specifically, hours between 6:00 a.m. and 11:00 a.m. or typically 9:00 a.m.",
      "answer": "เช้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "from",
      "answer": "จาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL watL deeM kha↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(spoken politely by a female) hello or goodbye",
      "answer": "สวัสดีค่ะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to sit or be sitting",
      "answer": "นั่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[see↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "four, the number or quantity four",
      "answer": "สี่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aan↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to read, <subject> reads",
      "answer": "อ่าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) good, well, fine, nice",
      "answer": "ดี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "over, above, on, upon, in",
      "answer": "บน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[see↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "color, colors, paint",
      "answer": "สี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "heart, spirit, spiritual center or core, soul, inner being, mind",
      "answer": "ใจ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jep↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) sore, hurt, injured, in pain, in emotional pain",
      "answer": "เจ็บ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gluaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) afraid (of), scared, frightened",
      "answer": "กลัว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL nook↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) fun, enjoyable, entertaining, amusing, pleasant",
      "answer": "สนุก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deuum↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to drink, <subject> drinks",
      "answer": "ดื่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(feeling) (is) cool, cold",
      "answer": "หนาว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuut↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to speak, to talk, to say",
      "answer": "พูด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laaeo↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(adverbial word indicating past tense or aspect marker indicating present perfect (past continued to present)) in the past, completed, still, to make done",
      "answer": "แล้ว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM thit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "week",
      "answer": "อาทิตย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawn↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to teach, to instruct, to train",
      "answer": "สอน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohnR jai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) interested (in), (is) attentive (to)",
      "answer": "สนใจ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khohn↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of the body, but not the head, of a human) hair",
      "answer": "ขน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[diaao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) single, alone",
      "answer": "เดียว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ram→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to dance",
      "answer": "รำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yai↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) big, large, huge, major, enormous, extensive, sizeable",
      "answer": "ใหญ่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL maan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "approximately, about, roughly",
      "answer": "ประมาณ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thook↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "every, each",
      "answer": "ทุก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaoF ee↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "chair",
      "answer": "เก้าอี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[huu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ear",
      "answer": "หู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to sleep, lie down",
      "answer": "นอน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[muu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "pork, meat of the pig",
      "answer": "หมู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpet↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "duck",
      "answer": "เป็ด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daawk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "flower",
      "answer": "ดอก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yoot↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to stop, halt",
      "answer": "หยุด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haam↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) forbidden, taboo, prohibited, banned",
      "answer": "ห้าม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "house, home, place (or one's place), village",
      "answer": "บ้าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baangM thee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "maybe, sometimes, perhaps",
      "answer": "บางที"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(word added at the end of a statement to indicate a question)",
      "answer": "ไหม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reuua→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "boat, ship, barge, vessel",
      "answer": "เรือ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawng↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "of, belonging to, that or those of, (a word used with a pronoun to indicate possesion, as in \"John's truck\")",
      "answer": "ของ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtawng↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(auxiliary verb) has to..., must..., is required to..., is duty-bound to...",
      "answer": "ต้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawt↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) deep-fried",
      "answer": "ทอด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) tea",
      "answer": "ชา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaw↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to ask for, to request, \"I'd like...\" — \"May/Can I have...?\"",
      "answer": "ขอ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wuaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cow, ox, bovine",
      "answer": "วัว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gae↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "sheep",
      "answer": "แกะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aawm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to conserve, save, economize",
      "answer": "ออม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gwiian→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cart, oxcart, wagon (typically) used to transport grain",
      "answer": "เกวียน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to hope, to expect, to want",
      "answer": "หวัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "according to",
      "answer": "ตาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR maa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "right, correct, honest, virtuous, righteous",
      "answer": "สัมมา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "state (pertaining to the government)",
      "answer": "หลวง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[la↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "each, every, one at a time, (implying division) per",
      "answer": "ละ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraaM goht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to appear, to seem, to reveal",
      "answer": "ปรากฏ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phra↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a title of ancient Thai civil nobility between พระยา  (Phraya) and หลวง  (Luang))",
      "answer": "พระ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khleuuan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to move to another place, to move or relocate in a supervised or organized fashion",
      "answer": "เคลื่อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raatF chaH gaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "civil service, public service, government service, bureaucracy",
      "answer": "ราชการ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL waang↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) bright, shining, illuminated",
      "answer": "สว่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thamM laai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to damage, harm, do harm, destroy, ruin, crush",
      "answer": "ทำลาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtem→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) complete, full",
      "answer": "เต็ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the day before",
      "answer": "วาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruuH seuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to feel or emote, to feel an emotion, to experience",
      "answer": "รู้สึก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ying↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "excessive, extreme",
      "answer": "ยิ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to pierce, puncture, prick",
      "answer": "ตำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "national, of a nation, race, of a country",
      "answer": "ชาติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(as a liquid) to flow or run, to slither",
      "answer": "ไหล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawt↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "budgetary item, grand total, total",
      "answer": "ยอด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ohk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) breast, chest",
      "answer": "อก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jamM nuaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "amount, number, quantity (of countable nouns)",
      "answer": "จำนวน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM phoot↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Wednesday",
      "answer": "วันพุธ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaH yaaM yaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to attempt, try, persevere, endeavor, make an effort",
      "answer": "พยายาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaH nit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "class, sort, type, variety, category, group, kind, species, in the style of...",
      "answer": "ชนิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kho:hm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lamp, lantern",
      "answer": "โคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bangM khap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to force, compel, command, control, coerce, enforce, compulsory, mandatory",
      "answer": "บังคับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheerm↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to increase, add, grow, advance, boost, develop, enlarge, enhance, escalate, expand, extend, multiply, raise, spread, swell, more",
      "answer": "เพิ่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "palace",
      "answer": "วัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuu↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "person, human, one (who...), (Thai prefix corresponding to the English suffixes) '-er' or '-or'",
      "answer": "ผู้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(3rd person singular or plural pronoun) he, she, him, her, they, them",
      "answer": "เขา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) equal, equivalent, even, as much as",
      "answer": "เท่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naH khaawn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "city, town, municipality",
      "answer": "นคร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to drive, operate, chauffer",
      "answer": "ขับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thoong↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "field, plain, pasture",
      "answer": "ทุ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM maH gaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "committee, board member",
      "answer": "กรรมการ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) serrated, notched",
      "answer": "จัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[boon→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "good deeds, merit",
      "answer": "บุญ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpluuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to cultivate, to plant, build, to grow a plant",
      "answer": "ปลูก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[john→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(most commonly used term) (is) poor, penniless, having nothing, impoverished",
      "answer": "จน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maanM daa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "mother",
      "answer": "มารดา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(used by females in an informal setting—also used by males with intimate friends or lovers) I, me, my",
      "answer": "ฉัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johp↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "end, finale",
      "answer": "จบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaam↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to ask (a question), to inquire, to quiz, to interrogate",
      "answer": "ถาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaen→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "instead",
      "answer": "แทน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to foretell, prophesy, predict, guess",
      "answer": "ทาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yuu↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "is (located at), to reside, to live (at), stay, exist at a particular point in time",
      "answer": "อยู่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rim→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "edge, rim, banks (of a river or canal)",
      "answer": "ริม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saap↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(polite) to know a fact or piece of information",
      "answer": "ทราบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maa↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "horse",
      "answer": "ม้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtriiam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to prepare, to be ready, to ready",
      "answer": "เตรียม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of an object) (is) old, antique, decrepit",
      "answer": "เก่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpuaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "in general, as a group, taken together",
      "answer": "ปวง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) vacant, free, available, empty",
      "answer": "ว่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL daat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "paper",
      "answer": "กระดาษ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to unfurl, to open, to stretch out, to spread out",
      "answer": "กาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raaM khaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "price, tariff, fare, cost, (coinage) denomination",
      "answer": "ราคา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL nan↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "consequently, thus",
      "answer": "ฉะนั้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaap↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to brace or splice with a long piece alongside",
      "answer": "ทาบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaae↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) genuine, real, true",
      "answer": "แท้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khreung↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "half, midway, mid, ½",
      "answer": "ครึ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to bring, take, head a procession, lead the way, conduct, show the way, carry, lead people or animals, take along",
      "answer": "พา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phleern→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "joyful, joyous, jovial, enjoyable, pleasurable, carried away",
      "answer": "เพลิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maehk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cloud",
      "answer": "เมฆ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawng↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "two, the number or quantity two",
      "answer": "สอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuuhr→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(used in intimate or informal settings) you (the 2nd person singular pronoun)",
      "answer": "เธอ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to persuade, to induce, to urge, to invite, to ask, to influence, to prevail upon, to agree",
      "answer": "ชวน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuuan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to slide, to slip, to glide, to skid",
      "answer": "เลื่อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[biia↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a small amount of money",
      "answer": "เบี้ย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rakH saa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to take care of, maintain, save",
      "answer": "รักษา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaH haan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "military, army, soldier",
      "answer": "ทหาร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) to die, be dead, perish, decease, expire, terminate, pass away, (car) stop (working)",
      "answer": "ตาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiaao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a trip, vacation, holiday, pleasure tour",
      "answer": "เที่ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wiH chaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of study) a subject, knowledge, branch of study",
      "answer": "วิชา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[doot↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "similar to, as if, as though",
      "answer": "ดุจ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM nai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "internal, inside",
      "answer": "ภายใน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaehn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "criteria, criterion, formula, specification, standard",
      "answer": "เกณฑ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giL riH yaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "action, manners, behavior, conduct",
      "answer": "กิริยา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "value, price, charge, cost, expense",
      "answer": "ค่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to steal, to pilfer, to pinch, to carry off",
      "answer": "ลัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaam↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "across from, opposite",
      "answer": "ข้าม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaae↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) defeated, lost",
      "answer": "แพ้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "flag",
      "answer": "ธง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuu↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) faithful, loyal, honest",
      "answer": "ซื่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saai↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "left direction (opposite of right)",
      "answer": "ซ้าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nakH bpraat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "philosopher",
      "answer": "นักปราชญ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheeM wit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "life",
      "answer": "ชีวิต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[no:hn↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "that one over there, a distant object",
      "answer": "โน้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nee↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to escape, elope, hurry away, flee",
      "answer": "หนี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thooH ra↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "business, personal business, errands",
      "answer": "ธุระ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaawn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a period of time, during..., an interval, when...",
      "answer": "ตอน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khraao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "occasion, time, episode",
      "answer": "คราว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to decree, lay down, formulate (laws, rules, regulations, questions)",
      "answer": "ตั้ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hohnR thaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "way, route, course, path",
      "answer": "หนทาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "circle, wheel, disk, discus, cycle",
      "answer": "จักร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[euun↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) other",
      "answer": "อื่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ga↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "guess, rough estimate",
      "answer": "กะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to construct, to begin to build",
      "answer": "ก่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sai↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to put in, add",
      "answer": "ใส่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL daang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) harsh, stiff, rough, coarse, crude, obstinate, rebellious, mutinous",
      "answer": "กระด้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "truth, enlightenment",
      "answer": "ธรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khwaang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to obstruct, impede, be in the way of, bar",
      "answer": "ขวาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hen↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to see, visualize",
      "answer": "เห็น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[miH thooL naaM yohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "June",
      "answer": "มิถุนายน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawM riH buun→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) perfect, complete, full, flawless",
      "answer": "บริบูรณ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jing→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "truthful, truthfully, really?, true, real, serious, no-nonsense, well, so",
      "answer": "จริง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nee↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "debt, liability",
      "answer": "หนี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chee↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to point (out), to indicate a location",
      "answer": "ชี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to connect",
      "answer": "ต่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(auxiliary verb used to indicate a command or order) should, ought to",
      "answer": "จง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtuaaM yaang↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "example, sample",
      "answer": "ตัวอย่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rohp↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to go to war, to fight, to make war, to battle",
      "answer": "รบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaen→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "substitute, replacement, deputized, representative",
      "answer": "แทน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuut↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ambassador, diplomat, emissary, envoy, attaché",
      "answer": "ทูต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lo:hk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the world, globe",
      "answer": "โลก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a guard, sentry, sentinel or night watchman",
      "answer": "ยาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to illuminate, enlighten, to shine or throw light upon",
      "answer": "ส่อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaF seuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "enemy",
      "answer": "ข้าศึก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohmR khuaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) suitable, proper, fitting, reasonable, appropriate, correct",
      "answer": "สมควร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL maaM khohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "association, organization, corporation",
      "answer": "สมาคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to say good-bye, to be on leave, to take one's leave, to bid farewell",
      "answer": "ลา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohp↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(charge, digit) negative, non-positive",
      "answer": "ลบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yeuun→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to stand",
      "answer": "ยืน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuM mi↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "earthen land, soil, site, grounds, floor, place",
      "answer": "ภูมิ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bangM geert↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to beget, produce, engender, conceive, pop up",
      "answer": "บังเกิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL yo:ht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "useful, beneficial",
      "answer": "ประโยชน์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khwaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) water buffalo",
      "answer": "ควาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "open, unfold, explain, unlock, tell, expand",
      "answer": "ไข"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtiiang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bed",
      "answer": "เตียง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaH na↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "faculty of a college or university",
      "answer": "คณะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) Saturn",
      "answer": "เสาร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to find, look for, seek, to search",
      "answer": "หา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) powered, motorized, mechanical",
      "answer": "ยนต์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to disappear, lose, lost, be missing",
      "answer": "หาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aehk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(usually used as an adjective) (is) sole, solitary, single, chief, first, prime, important, leading, excellent, one, alone, lonely",
      "answer": "เอก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[moht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) empty, finished, all used up, complete, lost",
      "answer": "หมด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheet↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "100 grams",
      "answer": "ขีด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohngM saaR waH daan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "annals, historical record, pedigree, chronicle, dynastic history",
      "answer": "พงศาวดาร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraatL thaL naa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to wish for, to desire",
      "answer": "ปรารถนา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phlik↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to turn over, to roll from side to side, to play tricks with, to twist",
      "answer": "พลิก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "army, fighting forces, force, troops, armed forces",
      "answer": "ทัพ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seung↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(the relative pronouns) who, whose, whom, of which",
      "answer": "ซึ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(spoken by a female to indicate an affirmative response) \"Yes\"",
      "answer": "ขา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "citizens, population, the people, the populace, the masses",
      "answer": "ราษฎร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "year, annum, annual",
      "answer": "ปี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawy↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "words, wording, speech, utterance, diction, verbal expression, statement, terms",
      "answer": "ถ้อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "word, term, discourse",
      "answer": "คำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aawk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the exit, the way out",
      "answer": "ออก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaeo↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) glass, transparent or translucent object, crystal, mica",
      "answer": "แก้ว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to have or possess, to be available",
      "answer": "มี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a trace, pathway, track, vestige, impression, imprint, a mark",
      "answer": "รอย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM aaM thit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Sunday",
      "answer": "วันอาทิตย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuup↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to search for the facts, to investigate, to detect, to trace, to track",
      "answer": "สืบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "mesh, structure, grid",
      "answer": "ร่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM phaH reuH hat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(colloquial) Thursday",
      "answer": "วันพฤหัสฯ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[banM yat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "legal act, law, decree, ordance, regulation",
      "answer": "บัญญัติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaaet↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "eight, the number or quantity eight",
      "answer": "แปด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to allow, yield, let, accept, agree to, is willing to",
      "answer": "ยอม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a prefix to a verb or adjective indicating a likely or probable state, as in the English suffix) \"-able\"",
      "answer": "น่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuua↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "in case of, provided that, if, for, in case (that)",
      "answer": "เผื่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ning↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) still, immobile, silent, motionless, quiet",
      "answer": "นิ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saam↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "three, the number or quantity three",
      "answer": "สาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "star, a non-planetary celestial body, spot",
      "answer": "ดาว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saatL saL naa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "religion, creed",
      "answer": "ศาสนา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL la↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to abandon, to renounce, to relinquish, to sacrifice, to foresake, to abdicate",
      "answer": "สละ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jeung→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "thus, therefore, so",
      "answer": "จึง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuun↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a room) floor, foundation, slab, underfloor",
      "answer": "พื้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to deceive, to gull, to dupe, to impose upon by craftiness or guile, to lure, entice or tempt into some snare or trap",
      "answer": "ลวง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mai↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) new, modern, fresh",
      "answer": "ใหม่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtamM naeng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "position, post, rank",
      "answer": "ตำแหน่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtruaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to check, test, examination, inspection",
      "answer": "ตรวจ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(formal, yet abbreviated) to eat",
      "answer": "ทาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(singular) person, (plural) people",
      "answer": "ชน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR raan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) content happy, reveling (in)",
      "answer": "สำราญ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khreuuang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "machine, apparatus, engine, mechanical device",
      "answer": "เครื่อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to claim, claim that",
      "answer": "อ้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "twist, turn",
      "answer": "ขัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM nit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "commerce, pertaining to commerce",
      "answer": "พาณิชย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "an attendant, servant, slave, a person under the authority of another",
      "answer": "ข้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL dtuu→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "door, gate, doorway, entrance",
      "answer": "ประตู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaM liH gaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "timepiece, clock, wristwatch, watch",
      "answer": "นาฬิกา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL laat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) strange, odd, weird, peculiar, wonderful, marvelous, queer, unusual, surprising",
      "answer": "ประหลาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deerm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the origin, beginning, start",
      "answer": "เดิม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laaeng↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) dry",
      "answer": "แล้ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "woman",
      "answer": "นาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM naaM jak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "kingdom, jurisdiction, realm, domain, dominion",
      "answer": "อาณาจักร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to sink, drown, submerge",
      "answer": "จม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawkF jaak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "except, unless, with the exception of..., other than..., besides, not only",
      "answer": "นอกจาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to beat, hit, strike, or whip",
      "answer": "ตี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[man→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(the indefinite pronoun for referring to animals or things) it, they",
      "answer": "มัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maaw↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "small container",
      "answer": "หม้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawy↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hundred, the number one hundred, 100",
      "answer": "ร้อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM noht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a schedule or appointment",
      "answer": "กำหนด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngaawk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to sprout, bud, grow, shoot off",
      "answer": "งอก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuua↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "for, on behalf of, for the purpose of...",
      "answer": "เพื่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daaen→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "border, land boundary, area, region",
      "answer": "แดน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawy↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(word used to soften the meaning of a sentence) \"...a bit\" — \"...somewhat\" — \"...to some extent\", this little thing, no big deal here, for just a moment",
      "answer": "หน่อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neuuang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) due to, related or connected to, a result of",
      "answer": "เนื่อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM see↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "tax, duty",
      "answer": "ภาษี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "telephone extension",
      "answer": "ต่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raai↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) bad, very bad, fierce, cruel, harmful, evil, wild",
      "answer": "ร้าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khuaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(auxiliary verb indicating) should, ought to, must",
      "answer": "ควร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaL waai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to give, offer, present",
      "answer": "ถวาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khee↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to ride upon, to drive (an animal, bicycle, or motorcycle)",
      "answer": "ขี่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dto:h→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) big, large, grown",
      "answer": "โต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(word added by a male speaker to the end of every sentence to convey politeness or) \"yes\", \"that's right\", \"I see.\"",
      "answer": "ครับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaL siL gam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "agriculture",
      "answer": "กสิกรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[boot↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "child, offspring, son or daughter",
      "answer": "บุตร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to cleave, split, or serrate",
      "answer": "จัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ja↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(auxiliary verb indicating future tense—must be used with another verb) will, shall",
      "answer": "จะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH leuk↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to think of, to recollect, to recall, to remember",
      "answer": "ระลึก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL gaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to announce, to proclaim, to declare, to notify, to publish",
      "answer": "ประกาศ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faL rang↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "non-Asian foreigner, (usually) Caucasian (see notes)",
      "answer": "ฝรั่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaL na↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "instant, moment, a short time, occasion, juncture, hour",
      "answer": "ขณะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "nest, home",
      "answer": "รัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[muu↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "group, race, flock, herd, crowd, corporation, company, collection, squad, clusters, series, class, genus, rove",
      "answer": "หมู่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to collide, to crash, bump, bump together",
      "answer": "ชน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaai↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to move or transfer",
      "answer": "ย้าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rapH bpraL thaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to dine, eat, sup, have a meal",
      "answer": "รับประทาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to battle",
      "answer": "ต่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuaa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "all, entire, complete, whole, throughout",
      "answer": "ทั่ว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuaa↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a bean or pea plant, a bean",
      "answer": "ถั่ว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[an→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "item, a small thing, piece",
      "answer": "อัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "against, towards, to, further, on",
      "answer": "ต่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "paper, sheet, card, ticket, document, blade",
      "answer": "ใบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gwaang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) wide, broad",
      "answer": "กว้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phoot↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Buddha",
      "answer": "พุทธ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM angM khaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Tuesday",
      "answer": "วันอังคาร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[o:hM roht↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "one's own son (legitimate) used by royalty",
      "answer": "โอรส"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seung↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(the relative pronouns) that, which",
      "answer": "ซึ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL sohng↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to wish or desire",
      "answer": "ประสงค์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to form into a rough shape, to trim, to clip (e.g. beard, bush)",
      "answer": "เกลา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtamM bohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "sub-district, a subdivision of the อำเภอ ",
      "answer": "ตำบล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maaw↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(informal) a medical doctor, a fortuneteller, a shaman",
      "answer": "หมอ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaen↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) tight, firm, secure",
      "answer": "แน่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[soht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) fresh, green, not spoiled, new, newly produced or minted, raw, (colors) bright",
      "answer": "สด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaaeng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "an explanation",
      "answer": "แจง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaap↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "existence, state, being, (a suffix corresponding to the English suffix \"-dom\")",
      "answer": "ภาพ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "active, energetic, vigorous, enthusiastic",
      "answer": "ขัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bookL khohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "person, individual, man, commoner",
      "answer": "บุคคล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to pass by, to be beyond, to be clear of",
      "answer": "พ้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "period of time designated as a shift or a watch for a sentinel or watchman",
      "answer": "ยาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maawn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Mon, Pegu, Peguan, an ethnic group of Burma and Thailand",
      "answer": "มอญ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "electric light, light switch",
      "answer": "ไฟ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hull, pod, sheath, case, nutshell",
      "answer": "ฝัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a short while",
      "answer": "พัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[angM grit↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "England, English, Great Britain, British",
      "answer": "อังกฤษ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaH na↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "council, group, member, corporation",
      "answer": "คณะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheuua↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bacteria, microbe, yeast, germ",
      "answer": "เชื้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giL laeht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lust, evil wish, desire, longing, greed, avarice, rapacity",
      "answer": "กิเลส"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daaet↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "sunlight, sunshine, sun, strong sunlight, rays of the sun",
      "answer": "แดด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohngR saan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "feel sorry for, to pity",
      "answer": "สงสาร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to bury, inter, put in the ground, implant",
      "answer": "ฝัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[booL ree↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cigarette",
      "answer": "บุหรี่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaep↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "nearly, almost",
      "answer": "แทบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the Moon",
      "answer": "จันทร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to break, be broken off, reflect, tax",
      "answer": "หัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to be related, to bind, to fasten together",
      "answer": "พันธ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheeuy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(auxiliary verb) used to..., did once...",
      "answer": "เคย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtohk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to fall, to drop or pour down, to fail",
      "answer": "ตก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lineage, family, dynasty, clan, kinship, descent, stock, race, multitude, assemblage, family (taxonomy)",
      "answer": "วงศ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to fight or quarrel with, accost, pick a fight with, to bully",
      "answer": "พาล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to combine, collect, add, include, incorporate, assemble, confederate",
      "answer": "รวม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nangR seuu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "book, document, letters, alphabet, printed document, written document",
      "answer": "หนังสือ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[feukL hat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to drill, practice, rehearse, to train",
      "answer": "ฝึกหัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuua↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(indicating a point in time) when, on (a date)",
      "answer": "เมื่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawR rap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(very formal polite particle used by a male)",
      "answer": "ขอรับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) rude, vulgar, impolite, obscene",
      "answer": "หยาบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bprohkL gaL dti↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) normal, usual, routine",
      "answer": "ปรกติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leerk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to quit, to stop, to give up, cancel, suspend, discontinue, abolish, cease, exit, split up",
      "answer": "เลิก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuut↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "plant, vegetation, fauna, seedling",
      "answer": "พืช"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL daaeng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to act, perform, demonstrate, show, or display",
      "answer": "แสดง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[than→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to overtake, catch up with, be on time, be abreast of",
      "answer": "ทัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maehM saaR yohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "April",
      "answer": "เมษายน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phleern→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to enjoy",
      "answer": "เพลิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suun↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "zero, the number or quantity zero",
      "answer": "ศูนย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheuua↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "flammable fuel",
      "answer": "เชื้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laayo→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) bad, inferior, worthless, base, vile",
      "answer": "เลว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaawp↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to scoop up with the hands",
      "answer": "กอบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "poison, toxin, venom",
      "answer": "พิษ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to resist, oppose, stop, withstand, impede, hinder, (the prefix) anti-",
      "answer": "ต้าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phreutH saL jiL gaaM yohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "November",
      "answer": "พฤศจิกายน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaL laat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "market, marketplace",
      "answer": "ตลาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "friend or friends",
      "answer": "มิตร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nan↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "that one, object at a medium distance, those",
      "answer": "นั้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) true, correct, right, conforming",
      "answer": "ถูก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaL raH gaL daaM khohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "July",
      "answer": "กรกฎาคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to bind, tie, attach",
      "answer": "ผูก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL maaM chik↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "member, subscriber",
      "answer": "สมาชิก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sin↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "property, wealth, riches, possessions",
      "answer": "สิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lem↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a book) a volume",
      "answer": "เล่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khwaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a prefix which converts an adjective or verb into a noun)",
      "answer": "ความ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baaep↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "plan, kind, design, pattern, style, model, type, (formal term officially endorsed by the Royal Institute) version (of software)",
      "answer": "แบบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[singR dto:h→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lion",
      "answer": "สิงโต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "in the clear, safe from",
      "answer": "พ้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL phaw↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) specific, particular, limited, provisional",
      "answer": "เฉพาะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khuun→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to multiply, mathematical multiplication, \"times\"",
      "answer": "คูณ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "often, frequently, inclined towards, prone towards",
      "answer": "มัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to lead or precede",
      "answer": "นำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phit↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) incorrect, wrong, mistaken, false, faulty, guilty",
      "answer": "ผิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaawngF gan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to defend, protect against, prevent, prevent against, bar",
      "answer": "ป้องกัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to lay down, to put down, to put on (airs), to deposit, to place, to set down",
      "answer": "วาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiapF raawy↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) polite and well mannered",
      "answer": "เรียบร้อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaae→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(impolite or colloquial usage) he, him, she, her, they, them, you",
      "answer": "แก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[loht↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to decrease, reduce, lower, diminish, lessen",
      "answer": "ลด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to push forward, to shove, to thrust",
      "answer": "ไส"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaL reern→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) prosperous",
      "answer": "เจริญ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to apply, paint, put on lotion or makeup",
      "answer": "ทา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thamM niiam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "custom, customs, tradition, traditional usage",
      "answer": "ธรรมเนียม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheun↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to ascend, raise, rise, go up",
      "answer": "ขึ้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaaiM haat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "beach",
      "answer": "ชายหาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bootL ree→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "daughter",
      "answer": "บุตรี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "virtue, morality, precept, scruples, rightneousness, principles, doctrine",
      "answer": "ธรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khraawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to rule, to govern, to regulate by authority, to exercise or assert authority, to direct",
      "answer": "ครอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naeH nam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of an idea) to introduce, suggest, advise, direct, guide, recommend",
      "answer": "แนะนำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaae↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "allergic to, have an allergy to",
      "answer": "แพ้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to pull at, to discount, draw, take away, withdraw, to pull upon",
      "answer": "ชัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bamM roong→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to care for, maintain, nurture, support",
      "answer": "บำรุง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "list of items, record, tally, story, account, item, statement, case",
      "answer": "ราย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to try, test, to experiment with, to try out",
      "answer": "ลอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ga↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to estimate or guess, to reckon, plan or plot",
      "answer": "กะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ying↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "excessively, extremely, very much, even more so",
      "answer": "ยิ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaL naat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "dimensions, size, measurement",
      "answer": "ขนาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ching→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to snatch away, to wrest away from, to contest or compete for, to vie",
      "answer": "ชิง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[moon↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to dial, turn, revolve, spin, rotate, whirl",
      "answer": "หมุน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawng↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "younger sibling, younger friend, younger colleague",
      "answer": "น้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lamM dap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "sequence, order, line, arrangement, series",
      "answer": "ลำดับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khoht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to roll into a coil, to coil, to bend, to twist",
      "answer": "ขด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a problem) to solve, to answer",
      "answer": "ทาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "dharma, religious teaching, religious duty",
      "answer": "ธรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lin↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "tongue",
      "answer": "ลิ้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khoht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "coil, ring, circle",
      "answer": "ขด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glaao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to speak, say, utter, tell or relate, to address, mention, declare",
      "answer": "กล่าว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gooL maan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "infant, child, boy, young lad, son, prince",
      "answer": "กุมาร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lid or cover of a pot or bowl, cap",
      "answer": "ฝา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaL giiang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lamp, oil lamp, lantern",
      "answer": "ตะเกียง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khraawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to occupy, to possess and enjoy the use of",
      "answer": "ครอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to plow, thrust, push, to clip hair very short",
      "answer": "ไถ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "post, pillar, pole, stake, lingam",
      "answer": "หลัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiH saeht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) special, particular, unique, extraordinary, extra",
      "answer": "พิเศษ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to row, to paddle",
      "answer": "พาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kha↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(word added by a female speaker to the end of every statement to convey politeness)",
      "answer": "ค่ะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[goomM phaaM phan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "February",
      "answer": "กุมภาพันธ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thang↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "all, entire, whole, wholly, both (...and), while",
      "answer": "ทั้ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gohtL maai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "law",
      "answer": "กฎหมาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[liiang↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to have a banquet, to hold a party or feast",
      "answer": "เลี้ยง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "folk, people, people of",
      "answer": "ชาว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yo:hn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to throw, pitch, cast, fling, hurl",
      "answer": "โยน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jamM bpen→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) necessary, essential, required, to need to (do something)",
      "answer": "จำเป็น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to bargain or haggle, to negotiate",
      "answer": "ต่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[o:h→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "pomelo citrus maxima",
      "answer": "โอ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaen↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "plan, pattern, scheme, project, model",
      "answer": "แผน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[theeM diaao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "quite, very",
      "answer": "ทีเดียว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaH na↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to conquer, defeat, beat, win",
      "answer": "ชนะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[muaak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hat, cap",
      "answer": "หมวก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[banM chaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to command, direct",
      "answer": "บัญชา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jet↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "seven, the number or quantity seven",
      "answer": "เจ็ด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "engineer, artisan, mechanic, craftsman, specialist, repairman, barber",
      "answer": "ช่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrohp↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) complete, whole, every, entire, due",
      "answer": "ครบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaaek↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "intersection",
      "answer": "แยก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neuk↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to suppose, think or conjecture, to feel, ponder, harbor a feeling or doubt,",
      "answer": "นึก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) circular, round",
      "answer": "กลม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glaa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "brave, fearless, courageous",
      "answer": "กล้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mohkH gaL raaM khohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "January",
      "answer": "มกราคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thee↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "at, on the site of, within, amidst, in the location of",
      "answer": "ที่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM sao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Saturday",
      "answer": "วันเสาร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) tight, confined, crowded, closely packed, tight-fitting, close-fitting",
      "answer": "คับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thohtH laawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to experiment, test",
      "answer": "ทดลอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raao→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "handrail, railing, rod, rack",
      "answer": "ราว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[singR haaR khohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "August",
      "answer": "สิงหาคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheuuang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) angry, peeved, indignant, wrathful, irate, offended, annoyed",
      "answer": "เคือง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruaam↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to share, join, partake, participate, unite, affiliate with, associate with, team with",
      "answer": "ร่วม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohp↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to erase",
      "answer": "ลบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sam↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) repeated, recurrent",
      "answer": "ซ้ำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yohk↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to raise, to hoist (up), to revoke, to advance, to abolish, to elevate, to lift, to erect",
      "answer": "ยก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giiatL khraan↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) lazy, indolent, idle, slothful, inert, inactive",
      "answer": "เกียจคร้าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thangH laai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "all, many, several",
      "answer": "ทั้งหลาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM sai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to inhabit, live in, or dwell in a place, to reside",
      "answer": "อาศัย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[anM dtaL raai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) dangerous, harmful, evil",
      "answer": "อันตราย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reuuan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "household, dwelling, abode, (typically a) wooden house",
      "answer": "เรือน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[siiang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "tone, sound, volume, noise",
      "answer": "เสียง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johtL maai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "postal letter, mail, a letter",
      "answer": "จดหมาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawngM kham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "gold, gold nugget",
      "answer": "ทองคำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL leung↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "salueng, 25 sadang, ¼ of 1 baht",
      "answer": "สลึง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM naawk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) outside, external",
      "answer": "ภายนอก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "section, portion, part (I, II, III, etc., of a movie or novel), region, division, side, segment, share, period, time",
      "answer": "ภาค"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohmR det↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "abbot, great one, a title of high rank for a queen and highly revered Buddhist priests",
      "answer": "สมเด็จ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiiang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "only, merely, up until the point, as much as, as far as, till, just until",
      "answer": "เพียง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaawng↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) synonymous, alike-sounding, identical, in agreement, coincident, simultaneous, allied",
      "answer": "พ้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[o:hM gaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "chance, opportunity, occasion",
      "answer": "โอกาส"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(royal use only) (prefix which transforms common verbs (and sometimes nouns) into the verbs (and nouns) for royal language showing actions of mounting (a horse) or holding (an object), etc. The meanings will depend on such ensuing verbs.)",
      "answer": "ทรง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sangR gaeht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to notice, to observe, to perceive, to recconoiter, to make a note of",
      "answer": "สังเกต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaaeng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "plot of land, flower bed, field",
      "answer": "แปลง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phreuH hatL saL baawM dee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(formal, general) Jupiter",
      "answer": "พฤหัสบดี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[matH thaH yohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "secondary education, high school",
      "answer": "มัธยม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "strong, intense, excessive, severe (especially when speaking of the weather)",
      "answer": "จัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "prince, princess, ruler, esteemed person, lord, master, holy being",
      "answer": "เจ้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "anyone, anybody, someone, somebody, whoever",
      "answer": "ใคร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaL reern→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to progress, grow, prosper, thrive, expand",
      "answer": "เจริญ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL waaeng↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to pursue, seek, look for, search out",
      "answer": "แสวง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to bear, stand, put up with, tolerate, endure, last",
      "answer": "ทน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kham↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "evening, dusk, sunset time",
      "answer": "ค่ำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiH saeht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "distinction, uniqueness, peculiarity, oddity",
      "answer": "พิเศษ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to enter, go in, to penetrate, to insert, to approach",
      "answer": "เข้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuuam↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to deteriorate, to depreciate, decrease, decline",
      "answer": "เสื่อม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiH thee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ceremony, event",
      "answer": "พิธี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naeH nam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a person) to introduce",
      "answer": "แนะนำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[siia↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) spent, broken, wasted, malfunctioning, defective, out of order, rotten, bad",
      "answer": "เสีย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hohk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "six, the number or quantity six",
      "answer": "หก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaae↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to undo, remedy, mend, repair, cure, correct, counteract, rectify, quench, slake, relieve, edit",
      "answer": "แก้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jeen→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "China, Chinese",
      "answer": "จีน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheet↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a scratch",
      "answer": "ขีด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaem↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "clear, bright, distinct, cheerful",
      "answer": "แจ่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "connector",
      "answer": "ต่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to do, make, perform, carry out, act",
      "answer": "กระทำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawt↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "top, pinnacle, tip, peak, summit, crown, zenith",
      "answer": "ยอด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chohnM laH bpraL thaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "irrigation",
      "answer": "ชลประทาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[look↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to rise, stand up, get up, arise",
      "answer": "ลุก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuuak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to select or choose, elect, pick",
      "answer": "เลือก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bo:hM raan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) ancient",
      "answer": "โบราณ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to speak, say, aver, think",
      "answer": "ว่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL thaaR nee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "station",
      "answer": "สถานี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rakH saa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to remedy, treat, or cure an illness",
      "answer": "รักษา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to hide, to conceal, to block the view, to screen, share or shield, to obscure",
      "answer": "บัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waaM jaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "speech, words, utterance, remarks, statements",
      "answer": "วาจา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawp↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cycle, round, circuit, trip, anniversary, revolution",
      "answer": "รอบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "face, front, facade, visage, (to nod) head",
      "answer": "หน้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaF thee↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "duty, function, obligation, responsibility",
      "answer": "หน้าที่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) callous, hard, hard-hearted, hardened, shameless",
      "answer": "ด้าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL dti↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "mindfulness, consciousness, mind, thought, sense, sensibility, sense of responsiveness, attention, attentiveness, reflection, balance",
      "answer": "สติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rim→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "by, beside, alongside, at the side of",
      "answer": "ริม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aL nooH yaat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to give permission or license, permit, allow, grant, consent",
      "answer": "อนุญาต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[geuuap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "almost, nearly, close to",
      "answer": "เกือบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to drag, pull at, haul",
      "answer": "ลาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheuun↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ground, land, foundation",
      "answer": "พื้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpleuuak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bark, rind, husk, shell, skin, peel",
      "answer": "เปลือก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[buuhr→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "number, digit",
      "answer": "เบอร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wiH thee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "method, way, mode of operation, procedure",
      "answer": "วิธี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thing↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to abandon, discard, throw away, to leave (an object) behind",
      "answer": "ทิ้ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thangH bpuaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "all, in total, completely, of every kind, as a whole",
      "answer": "ทั้งปวง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to adjust, arrange, fix",
      "answer": "จัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) beautiful, pretty, attractive, gorgeous, fine, complete",
      "answer": "งาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaaeng↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to notify, advise, inform, make apparent",
      "answer": "แจ้ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to tattoo",
      "answer": "สัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to shut, sleep, to be asleep, go to bed",
      "answer": "หลับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to fetch (someone), to send for (someone)",
      "answer": "ตาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to hitch, to link, to hook up",
      "answer": "เกี่ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "root, foundation, source",
      "answer": "ราก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[daan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "side, face, direction, quarter, sector, aspect, surface, field, viewpoint",
      "answer": "ด้าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baeng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to share, divide into parts, apportion",
      "answer": "แบ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sinR khaa↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "merchandise, product, finished good",
      "answer": "สินค้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL watL deeM khrap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(spoken politely by a male) hello, goodbye",
      "answer": "สวัสดีครับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpaL dtiL bat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to execute, perform, do, act, behave, practice",
      "answer": "ปฏิบัติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sen↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "geometric line, string, filament, thread, rope, cord, route or routing, ply",
      "answer": "เส้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[biia↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a counter used in gambling",
      "answer": "เบี้ย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laae→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to look at, to watch, to see, to glance, to take a look",
      "answer": "แล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "person, guy, people, man, human being",
      "answer": "คน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to trade, to do business, to do commerce, to barter, to buy and sell, to vend, to traffic in",
      "answer": "ค้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM rai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "profit, gain",
      "answer": "กำไร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraH yaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(title of ancient Thai civil nobility nobility between พระ  (Phra) and เจ้าพระยา  (Chao Phraya))",
      "answer": "พระยา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chat↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) sharp, clear, focused, concise",
      "answer": "ชัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR ret↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to succeed, finish, complete, accomplish",
      "answer": "สำเร็จ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graehng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) afraid, fearful, inspired with awe, respectful of, fearful, filled with reverence",
      "answer": "เกรง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to go against, to stop, to hinder, to oppose, to obstruct, to block",
      "answer": "ขัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suaam↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to wear, to put on, to dress with, to cover, to clothe",
      "answer": "สวม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiian→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to add to, to augment, to supplement",
      "answer": "เพียน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[fak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "gourd, squash Cucurbita",
      "answer": "ฟัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "several, numerous, a variety, many, sundry, diverse, (the prefix) \"multi-\"",
      "answer": "หลาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to wind (up) or unwind, to turn",
      "answer": "ไข"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaang↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "variety, style, pattern, type, kind, sort, mode, manner, method",
      "answer": "อย่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "animal fat, lard, tallow, (of human bones) marrow",
      "answer": "ไข"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sanR seern↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to praise, admire, laud",
      "answer": "สรรเสริญ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "body, human body, physique",
      "answer": "กาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faa↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the sky, firmament, heaven",
      "answer": "ฟ้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maH laaeng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bug, insect",
      "answer": "แมลง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) loud, noisy",
      "answer": "ดัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheuu→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(copula) to be, (conjunction used for equivalence definitions)",
      "answer": "คือ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sam↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to repeat, to recur, to reiterate",
      "answer": "ซ้ำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "form, figure, style",
      "answer": "ทรง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(referring to placement in space or time) location",
      "answer": "ภาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtam↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) low, short, depressed, base",
      "answer": "ต่ำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaaoL khaawng↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) involved, concerned",
      "answer": "เกี่ยวข้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suaan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "garden, field, park, farm, plantation",
      "answer": "สวน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "general, General (military rank)",
      "answer": "พล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hohm↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cover, close",
      "answer": "ห่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[damM neern→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to implement, to go forward with a plan, to conduct or proceed, to operate, carry out",
      "answer": "ดำเนิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaenL din→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "land, country, kingdom, ground, earth, plot of land",
      "answer": "แผ่นดิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtooL laaM khohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "October",
      "answer": "ตุลาคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "skin, complexion, surface",
      "answer": "ผิว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawng↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "belly, abdomen, stomach",
      "answer": "ท้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bohtL banM naaM thiH gaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "editorial",
      "answer": "บทบรรณาธิการ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naaen↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) crowded, busy (restaurant, etc), tightly packed",
      "answer": "แน่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to look at with a telescope, microscope, or binoculars",
      "answer": "ส่อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaen↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "sheet, tablet, plank, strip, piece",
      "answer": "แผ่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaL laawt↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "during, all during, throughout, through, in (e.g., in over 20 years)",
      "answer": "ตลอด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khuu→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ditch, moat",
      "answer": "คู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to mow or harvest, reap, cut",
      "answer": "เกี่ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH ngap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to halt, to curb, to stop, cease, mitigate, check suppress, repress",
      "answer": "ระงับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the middle, the center",
      "answer": "กลาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to confine, coop up, imprison, retain, detain, cage, incarcerate",
      "answer": "ขัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a medical condition or other problem) (is) serious",
      "answer": "หนัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohnM laH meuuang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a citizen, an inhabitant, people, population",
      "answer": "พลเมือง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtohn↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a prefix used for plant or tree names) plant, stalk, trunk, tree",
      "answer": "ต้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gro:hng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "apothecary's mortar",
      "answer": "โกร่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtatL sin↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to decide, judge, referee",
      "answer": "ตัดสิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lo:hk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the planet Earth",
      "answer": "โลก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to mold, form, fabricate",
      "answer": "ปั้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohp↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "mathematical subtraction, minus",
      "answer": "ลบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(word used before a verb or noun to describe a profession) person who, enthusiast, devotee, expert",
      "answer": "นัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[grohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of government) a department",
      "answer": "กรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrang↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(frequency) time, occasion, instance, event, occurrence",
      "answer": "ครั้ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of ranking and order) deputy, vice-, subordinate, associate, secondary, (competition, status of wife) second, next",
      "answer": "รอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaawn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "worker, laborer, doer, workman, (a suffix indicating) a person who... (does certain things), or an object that... (performs a certain function)",
      "answer": "กร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaH yaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "witness",
      "answer": "พยาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phanM raH yaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "wife",
      "answer": "ภรรยา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL naam↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "field, park, lawn, playground, meadow, yard, turf, grassy field",
      "answer": "สนาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "jungle, thick grove",
      "answer": "ดง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jangM wat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "province, of which Thailand has 76",
      "answer": "จังหวัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(suffix indicating qualification, quantification, or interrogation, as indicated below)",
      "answer": "ไร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Thai currency: Baht (TH฿)",
      "answer": "บาท"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawy↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to withdraw, move back, retreat",
      "answer": "ถอย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaM chaat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a red cross",
      "answer": "กาชาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[liaao↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to turn, make a change in direction",
      "answer": "เลี้ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohmR moot↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to assume, suppose",
      "answer": "สมมุติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraawm↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) ready, set, finished, complete",
      "answer": "พร้อม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) (is) teak",
      "answer": "สัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maaw↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a pot for cooking",
      "answer": "หม้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaL sat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) king",
      "answer": "กษัตริย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohngR sai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to doubt, suspect, wonder about",
      "answer": "สงสัย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL ra↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a vowel",
      "answer": "สระ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gep↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to collect, preserve, keep, fetch",
      "answer": "เก็บ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to eliminate, to stop, to die or pass away",
      "answer": "ดับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thanM waaM khohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "December",
      "answer": "ธันวาคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gro:ht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) mad, angry, pissed off",
      "answer": "โกรธ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lamM phang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "individual, private, personal",
      "answer": "ลำพัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chamM naan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) experienced, skilled, expert, adroit",
      "answer": "ชำนาญ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuup↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to succeed, to pass on to another, to continue, to advance",
      "answer": "สืบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngaai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) easy, not difficult, simple",
      "answer": "ง่าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seek↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "section, piece, part, portion (as in the English prefix) hemi-",
      "answer": "ซีก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "South, Southern",
      "answer": "ใต้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuuan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to postpone",
      "answer": "เลื่อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohm↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) becoming, suitable for, appropriate, conforming, worthy of",
      "answer": "สม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[napH theuu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to respect, esteem, revere, reckon, hold in high regard, believe in, profess",
      "answer": "นับถือ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL muuhr↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) even, level, flush",
      "answer": "เสมอ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to halt, lay-over, stop for the night, stay overnight at a place, to rest or relax, remain at a place temporarily",
      "answer": "พัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phlaawy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "gem, gems, gemstones, jewels, jewelry",
      "answer": "พลอย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawM riH sat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "company, firm, corporation, congregration, audience, meeting, assembly",
      "answer": "บริษัท"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngo:h↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) stupid, silly, dumb, foolish, vain",
      "answer": "โง่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaH weep↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "continent",
      "answer": "ทวีป"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[banM daa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "all, in general, those",
      "answer": "บรรดา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) scarce, limited, few, rare, thin",
      "answer": "บาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "teapot-kettle with a spout, tick, sign or mark set against an item",
      "answer": "กา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohmR bat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "assets, treasure, fortune, riches, wealth",
      "answer": "สมบัติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "shape, figure, body, outline, form",
      "answer": "ร่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khiian↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to write, to draw",
      "answer": "เขียน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to make a check-mark, X or cross marks",
      "answer": "กา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sip↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ten, the number or quantity ten",
      "answer": "สิบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chen↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "as",
      "answer": "เช่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khiiang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) adjoining, connected, beside, near, close together",
      "answer": "เคียง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaeh→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to take away in large numbers, to haul off, to pour",
      "answer": "เท"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hair style, hairdo",
      "answer": "ทรง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruup↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "shape, form, contour, appearance, similarity-to",
      "answer": "รูป"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khran↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "when (something occurs), if (something happened)",
      "answer": "ครั้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yeeF bpoon↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Japan",
      "answer": "ญี่ปุ่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaehM waH daa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a male angel",
      "answer": "เทวดา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL phaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bridge, pier",
      "answer": "สะพาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saaR mee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "husband",
      "answer": "สามี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH ya↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a space, interval or separation (as in punctuation), a period, a stage, distance, time",
      "answer": "ระยะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chan↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "class, rank, grade",
      "answer": "ชั้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM sook↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Friday",
      "answer": "วันศุกร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thet↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) false, untrue, dishonest, deceptive, spurious",
      "answer": "เท็จ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheung↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "just now, a moment ago, recently",
      "answer": "พึ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of contracts, ropes, etc.) to extend, to lengthen, (of phone calls) to connect, (of words) to join, to link, (of knowledge) to receive or inherit",
      "answer": "ต่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saehR naaM baawM dee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "secretary of state, minister, commander in chief",
      "answer": "เสนาบดี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtit↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a person) to become (figuratively) fixated (on something), to think about (something) to an extreme and excessive degree, to be (figuratively) absorbed, to be obsessed (with someone or something), to be crazy or mad about, to be fascinated by",
      "answer": "ติด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL thaan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "place, site, location, locality",
      "answer": "สถาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[uaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to boast, brag, show off, display, flaunt",
      "answer": "อวด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saaR maat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) capable, able",
      "answer": "สามารถ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaeng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to compete, to race, to contend with, to strive for, to vie",
      "answer": "แข่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thook↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "suffering, sorrow, distress, adversity, trouble, anxiety, first of the Four Noble Truths",
      "answer": "ทุกข์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "relative, kin, relations, cousins",
      "answer": "ญาติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR nak↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "office, bureau, institute, institution",
      "answer": "สำนัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rohm↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "umbrella, parasol",
      "answer": "ร่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL jaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to disperse, distribute, broadcast, spread, scatter",
      "answer": "กระจาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruu→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "tiny hole, cavity, gap",
      "answer": "รู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[geern→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to exceed, go beyond, overreach, surpass",
      "answer": "เกิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "beat, pound an object, pulverize",
      "answer": "ตำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[noom↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "teenage male, young man, adolescent",
      "answer": "หนุ่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khohn↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to search",
      "answer": "ค้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mangF mee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) rich, wealthy, affluent, opulent",
      "answer": "มั่งมี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[akL saawn↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "alphabet, (of the alphabet:) letter, character, glyph, word, sound, vowels, consonants",
      "answer": "อักษร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawM riH soot↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) innocent, pure, uncontaminated, virgin, fine",
      "answer": "บริสุทธิ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraiM saL nee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "post, mail, post office, postal system",
      "answer": "ไปรษณีย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[nap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to count",
      "answer": "นับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faai↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "side, party, faction, group",
      "answer": "ฝ่าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naawk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) outside of, external to, foreign, alien",
      "answer": "นอก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[siiaR jai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) very sorry, grieving",
      "answer": "เสียใจ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaawy↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to let go, relinquish, discharge, emit, abandon, release, ease",
      "answer": "ปล่อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL choom→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to assemble, have a meeting",
      "answer": "ประชุม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL wan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "heaven, paradise",
      "answer": "สวรรค์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[noong↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to dress, don, put on, wear clothing, to get dressed, attire, clothe, garb, robe, slip on or into",
      "answer": "นุ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laH iiat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) detailed, exact, delicate, fine, powdered, finely powdered, meticulous, careful, thorough, methodical",
      "answer": "ละเอียด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaam↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to cross over, pass over, step over",
      "answer": "ข้าม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[boht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "chapter of a book, lesson of a schoolbook, article in a magazine, verse, stanza",
      "answer": "บท"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[diaaoR nee↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "now, nowadays, \"Right now!\", \"Pronto!\"",
      "answer": "เดี๋ยวนี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuay↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to help, to aid, to assist, to contribute, to please",
      "answer": "ช่วย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baai↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "afternoon hours between 1:00 p.m. and 4:00 p.m.",
      "answer": "บ่าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to tear, rip or become torn or ripped asunder, to separate",
      "answer": "ขาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuM mi↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) grand, proud, dignified",
      "answer": "ภูมิ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saaeng↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "light, ray, light ray, beam of light",
      "answer": "แสง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpro:ht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a formal word of request) \"please\"",
      "answer": "โปรด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mee↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bear (the animal)",
      "answer": "หมี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[theert↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a formal word placed after a verb or a sentence to mark or indicate an exhortation, a command or an entreaty) let's, let us, let's go for it, let's do it",
      "answer": "เถิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[feuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to drill, to train, to practice, to exercise, to teach",
      "answer": "ฝึก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "one of the four ancient elements: earth, water, air, or fire",
      "answer": "ธาตุ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) clear, transparent",
      "answer": "ใส"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL phreut↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "manner, conduct, deportment, behavior",
      "answer": "ประพฤติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[biL daa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "father",
      "answer": "บิดา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaan↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) pure, absolute, pristine",
      "answer": "ล้วน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiH jaaM raH naa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to consider, to appraise, to study, to examine, to investigate, to reckon",
      "answer": "พิจารณา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL daan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "game board",
      "answer": "กระดาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[man→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "oil, fat, grease",
      "answer": "มัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to concern",
      "answer": "เกี่ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phreutH saL phaaM khohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "May",
      "answer": "พฤษภาคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[len↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to play, have fun, enjoy, amuse, jest, have fun on the Internet",
      "answer": "เล่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maehtF dtaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(Buddhism) goodwill, kindness, mercy, clemency, compassion, kindheartedness",
      "answer": "เมตตา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraapL bpraam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to repress, quell, quash, subjugate",
      "answer": "ปราบปราม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawy↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "gently, softly, little by little, gradually, cautiously",
      "answer": "ค่อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sanR yaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "legal contract, promise, agreement, treaty, pact, deal",
      "answer": "สัญญา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiiam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) artificial, false, imitation",
      "answer": "เทียม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raaM chaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "royal, of or pertaining to king",
      "answer": "ราชา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faawng↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to sue",
      "answer": "ฟ้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[diaao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "soon, shortly, momentarily",
      "answer": "เดี๋ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mohnM thohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "precinct, administrative region",
      "answer": "มณฑล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) thick, (of fabric) heavy",
      "answer": "หนา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maai↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "wood, woods, forest, stick, rod",
      "answer": "ไม้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maH noot↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "human being, man, human, homo sapiens",
      "answer": "มนุษย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL gaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "bill",
      "answer": "ประกาศ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[git↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "errand, duty, work, routine, affair, business",
      "answer": "กิจ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "together with",
      "answer": "กัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL nee↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "consequently, so, thus",
      "answer": "ฉะนี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaaeng↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to catch, to seize, to scramble for, contend for, compete for, wrest",
      "answer": "แย่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[samR rap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "for, as for, in order to, for the purpose of, in order that",
      "answer": "สำหรับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "young woman, girl, unmarried woman, maiden, damsel, lass, lassie (informal), maid, virgin, wench",
      "answer": "สาว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL daan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "board, plank, deal",
      "answer": "กระดาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaH nuaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fuse, primer, harbinger",
      "answer": "ชนวน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuua↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "tiger",
      "answer": "เสือ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM sit↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "saying, proverb, motto, saw, teaching, maxim, adage",
      "answer": "ภาษิต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maaeo→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cat",
      "answer": "แมว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to arrest, catch, get a hold of, touch, capture, seize",
      "answer": "จับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[din→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "dirt, earth, soil, ground, land, kingdom, realm",
      "answer": "ดิน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaoF huu↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to hear, to have heard",
      "answer": "เข้าหู"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaw↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "joint, point of intersection, articulation",
      "answer": "ข้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maawk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fog, mist, foggy, misty",
      "answer": "หมอก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM noht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to schedule, set, limit, appoint, settle, condition, agree upon, assign, specify, define, establish",
      "answer": "กำหนด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(Thai transcription of the foreign loanword) sure, surely, certainly",
      "answer": "ชัวร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[deuuat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to boil by heat, to be iritated, to be provoked, to boil over, to be furious, to be in a rage",
      "answer": "เดือด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiiap↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to compare, to place alongside, to escort",
      "answer": "เทียบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to hire, engage, employ",
      "answer": "จ้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaL wan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the Sun",
      "answer": "ตะวัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gamM lang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(auxiliary verb indicating the present participle, meaning \"in the act of\" or \"in the process of\", similar to the English suffix, \"-ing\")",
      "answer": "กำลัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to cut, mow, trim, sever, hew, make (a suit), build (a road)",
      "answer": "ตัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiapF raawy↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) neat, ready, all set, all in order, orderly, tidy",
      "answer": "เรียบร้อย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khlaai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to diminish, to unwind, to relax, to slacken, to abate, to lessen, to untwist, to unfurl, to decrease",
      "answer": "คลาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaai↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "at the back, at the end",
      "answer": "ท้าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpanM yaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(Buddhism) intelligence, wisdom, sharpness, wit",
      "answer": "ปัญญา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtrat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(as a king or royalty) to say, remark, speak, declare, pronounce",
      "answer": "ตรัส"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaH dee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lawsuit, legal action, case",
      "answer": "คดี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hohm↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to cover, clothe, wrap, enclose, dress",
      "answer": "ห่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dteuuan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to caution, warn, remind",
      "answer": "เตือน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[damM ri↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(Royal use only) to think",
      "answer": "ดำริ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jamM phuaak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "species, type, group",
      "answer": "จำพวก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) in short supply, not on hand, lacking, needing",
      "answer": "ขาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "basis, foundation, principle, maxim, doctrine, tenet",
      "answer": "หลัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a bowl or basin used for dipping water",
      "answer": "ขัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM nai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "within, by (a certain time frame)",
      "answer": "ภายใน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laehn↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "great-grandchild",
      "answer": "เหลน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phiiangM rai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "how many",
      "answer": "เพียงไร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mohnM dtree→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "a high government official or adviser, a mandarin",
      "answer": "มนตรี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to remember, recall, memorize, retain, recognize, recollect",
      "answer": "จำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpleuuang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to use up, consume, waste",
      "answer": "เปลือง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to exceed, overstep, pass, to go beyond",
      "answer": "ล่วง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to extinguish, put out, vanquish, dead",
      "answer": "ดับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL mai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "era, times, period, age",
      "answer": "สมัย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khrai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to desire, wish, prefer",
      "answer": "ใคร่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "deed, kamma, karma, sin, bad karma earned",
      "answer": "กรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aL maehM riH gaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "America, United States, American",
      "answer": "อเมริกา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giaao↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) entangled with, (is) hugging, (is) embracing",
      "answer": "เกี่ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aL thiH baai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to explain, define, describe",
      "answer": "อธิบาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM naaM khaeht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "territory",
      "answer": "อาณาเขต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thamM maH daa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) usual, ordinary, normal, average, plain, regular, natural, common",
      "answer": "ธรรมดา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[seuua↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "shirt, blouse, jacket",
      "answer": "เสื้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to place on top of or overlay, superimpose, run over",
      "answer": "ทับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maakF maai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "very much, plentiful, much, many, countless, various, several, a lot of, many, diversified, miscellaneous, numerous",
      "answer": "มากมาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[booL root↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "man, male, gentleman, person, people, mankind, humans",
      "answer": "บุรุษ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtuu↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "storage cabinet, post office box, cupboard, locker for luggage, (gym clothing) locker",
      "answer": "ตู้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtrohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) straight, direct, exactly, upright, vertical",
      "answer": "ตรง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a person) party, side, sort, type",
      "answer": "ขา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "warrant, notice, order, point, writ, summons, decree",
      "answer": "หมาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL bap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "edition, copy, issue of a magazine or newspaper, (formal term officially endorsed by the Royal Institute) version (of software)",
      "answer": "ฉบับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtai↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to climb, to scale (a mountain), to move up slowly and carefully",
      "answer": "ไต่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH waang↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "between, in the middle of, the middle, among",
      "answer": "ระหว่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leek↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to avoid, evade, dodge, get out of the way",
      "answer": "หลีก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM lang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "afterward, later, afterwards",
      "answer": "ภายหลัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faawng↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to accuse, prosecute",
      "answer": "ฟ้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpliian↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to change, replace, to convert, to alter, swap, substitute, to transplant",
      "answer": "เปลี่ยน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aapL naam↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to bathe, take a bath, take a shower, swim",
      "answer": "อาบน้ำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheeuy↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to open, to disclose, to discover, to unveil, to uncover, to reveal",
      "answer": "เผย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[mai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to burn",
      "answer": "ไหม้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laH aawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "dust, spray, mist, particles, fine particles, powder, fall-out",
      "answer": "ละออง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "harm, danger, catastrophe, fear, dread, peril",
      "answer": "ภัย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[amM naat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "authority, power",
      "answer": "อำนาจ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jo:ht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "accusation, objection",
      "answer": "โจทย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[niH thaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fable, story, yarn, tale, folklore, fairytale",
      "answer": "นิทาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[than↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a respectful 2nd or 3rd person singular pronoun) you, he, she, him, her",
      "answer": "ท่าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sook↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "happiness, content, bliss, pleasure",
      "answer": "สุข"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaL rit↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "behavior, conduct, act (outward act)",
      "answer": "จริต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to relate a story, to tell, to recount, to narrate",
      "answer": "เล่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaai↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "stern, back, rear end",
      "answer": "ท้าย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtraa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "brand name, brand, seal, stamp, mark, hallmark, device, decoration, badge",
      "answer": "ตรา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khwaang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to throw, to pitch, to toss, to hurl, to cast, to fling",
      "answer": "ขว้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaw→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) sufficient, (does) suffice, (is) adequate, enough",
      "answer": "พอ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL dtree→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "female, woman, lady",
      "answer": "สตรี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuk↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) deep",
      "answer": "ลึก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sang↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to order merchandise, food, or medicine",
      "answer": "สั่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the rai, a unit of land measure",
      "answer": "ไร่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khai↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fever, a temperature of the body, sickness",
      "answer": "ไข้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ganM yaaM yohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "September",
      "answer": "กันยายน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to come down, go down, get off, get out of, descend, land",
      "answer": "ลง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suu↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to face, to be against",
      "answer": "สู้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaF raatF chaH gaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "government official, civil servant",
      "answer": "ข้าราชการ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sook↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) Venus",
      "answer": "ศุกร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tho:ht↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "punishment, penalty, penance, guilt, blame, offence, crime, penalty, ill-effect, harm, danger, fault, defect, sinfulness, misdeed",
      "answer": "โทษ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaap↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "image, picture, drawing, vision",
      "answer": "ภาพ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yoht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of liquid) a drop",
      "answer": "หยด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[han↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to turn oneself around, to face in a direction",
      "answer": "หัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meuuaF rai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(used in a question) when",
      "answer": "เมื่อไร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuuM mi↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "status, standing",
      "answer": "ภูมิ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL nan↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "in that way, like that",
      "answer": "กระนั้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaawn↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to herd, or corner, gather together",
      "answer": "ต้อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohngR khraam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "war, battle, hostilities, conflict, combat",
      "answer": "สงคราม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL phaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "council, assembly",
      "answer": "สภา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[beuuang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(prefix for a (spatial) direction)",
      "answer": "เบื้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[atL raa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "rate, rating, criteria, established scale, limit, standard, class, grade, standing",
      "answer": "อัตรา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "some, any, partially",
      "answer": "บ้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yootH dtiL tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) fair, just",
      "answer": "ยุติธรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL thaeht↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "nation, country",
      "answer": "ประเทศ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "turn, outing, chance, opportunity, instance, times, occasion",
      "answer": "ที"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaiM nai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the inside, the interior",
      "answer": "ภายใน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[suung↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) tall, high, advanced",
      "answer": "สูง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[oht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to abstain (from food, e.g.), fast, refrain, cease",
      "answer": "อด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaawy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to wait or wait for",
      "answer": "คอย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phim→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to print, type, importing, make an impression of",
      "answer": "พิมพ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[joht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to take note, to jot down",
      "answer": "จด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "gold, Au",
      "answer": "ทอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaawng↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "passage, aperature, gap, hole, lane, opening, (euphonious word for บ้าน )",
      "answer": "ช่อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lohm↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to fall down",
      "answer": "ล้ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(used with another verb to indicate possibility) may, might",
      "answer": "อาจ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wen↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to exclude, omit, skip over",
      "answer": "เว้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leerk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "separate from another person, to break up a relationship",
      "answer": "เลิก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[duay↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "together, along with, also, too, as well, likewise, in addition to doing some other thing (as another action performed by the same subject)",
      "answer": "ด้วย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaawp↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to answer, reply, respond, in return",
      "answer": "ตอบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raangM wan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "award, prize, reward",
      "answer": "รางวัล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to look at, to see, to stare at, to glance, to eye",
      "answer": "มอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laH khaawn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) theatrical presentation",
      "answer": "ละคร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaL nohn↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "road, boulevard, avenue, street",
      "answer": "ถนน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reep↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to hurry",
      "answer": "รีบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawt↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "excellent, superb, perfect, great",
      "answer": "ยอด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaae↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to expand, spread out, diffuse, stretch out, extend, broaden, unfold, unroll",
      "answer": "แผ่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpanM haa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "problem, trouble, difficulty",
      "answer": "ปัญหา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[giiatL dtiL yoht↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "honor, prestige, fame, renown, reputation, dignity",
      "answer": "เกียรติยศ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[oom↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to carry, hold (in arms), to cradle",
      "answer": "อุ้ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaeht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "boundary, border, limit, district, territory, zone",
      "answer": "เขต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laan↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "million, the number one million (1,000,000)",
      "answer": "ล้าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laH laai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to dissolve, melt",
      "answer": "ละลาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaeo↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of objects) a row, column, file, line, bank, queue",
      "answer": "แถว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[duaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "orb, spherical object, astrological sign, stars",
      "answer": "ดวง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "rule, law, regulation",
      "answer": "ธรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thit↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a named) direction or point of the compass (such as east, west, north, and south, or right and left), a quarter section of the horizon",
      "answer": "ทิศ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawn↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to conceal or hide an item or oneself",
      "answer": "ซ่อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "asset, wealth, possessions, riches",
      "answer": "ทรัพย์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bohk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "land, dry land, terra firma, high ground",
      "answer": "บก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaL yaai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to expand, enlarge, amplify, inflate, magnify",
      "answer": "ขยาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "greatly, extremely, truly, fully, quite, most, very much so",
      "answer": "จัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "wire, line, rope, string, strap, connection, tie",
      "answer": "สาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(placed before a verb or noun to create a noun which indicates a general activity, process, or state) the process of..., the activity of..., an enactment of..., the state of... (see notes)",
      "answer": "การ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[pheung→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(written) should, ought, ought to",
      "answer": "พึง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maae↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "though, if, provided, even, even if",
      "answer": "แม้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to call out, called, to be named",
      "answer": "เรียก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL mang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "likely as not, perhaps, maybe, probably",
      "answer": "กระมัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rai↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) without, lacking, devoid of, in need of",
      "answer": "ไร้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "nine, the number or quantity nine",
      "answer": "เก้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "justice, fairness",
      "answer": "ธรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraatL saL jaak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) without, separate from, (is) rid of, (is) free from",
      "answer": "ปราศจาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaw↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ditch",
      "answer": "ท่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aawn↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) soft, pliable, tender",
      "answer": "อ่อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ying→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to fire or shoot (a gun)",
      "answer": "ยิง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to miss or be absent from an event",
      "answer": "ขาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[manF khohng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) secure, stable, firm, solid, sturdy",
      "answer": "มั่นคง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phoot↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) Mercury",
      "answer": "พุธ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "below, under, down below, underneath",
      "answer": "ล่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "low member of military or police force",
      "answer": "พล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(specifiying temporal sequence) next, afterward, later on, continued",
      "answer": "ต่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chen↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "example, sample, specimen",
      "answer": "เช่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL yo:ht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "benefit, use, usefulness",
      "answer": "ประโยชน์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohngR sai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) suspicious",
      "answer": "สงสัย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[groong→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "city, town, capital city",
      "answer": "กรุง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL seert↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) excellent, glorious, sublime, superb, outstanding",
      "answer": "ประเสริฐ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[amM phuuhr→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "district, a subdivision of a Thai province",
      "answer": "อำเภอ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[wanM jan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Monday",
      "answer": "วันจันทร์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaaeng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to convert, modify, adapt",
      "answer": "แปลง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaek↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "visitor, guest, foreigner",
      "answer": "แขก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[liiang↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to feed, nourish, nurture, raise a child or animal, provide for, rear, bring up, foster, nurse",
      "answer": "เลี้ยง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaaF phaH jao↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a first person pronoun) I, me, my (used when writing or speaking formally)",
      "answer": "ข้าพเจ้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to polish, scrub, rub, abrade, burnish",
      "answer": "ขัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaaM haL na↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "vehicle, carrier, transport",
      "answer": "พาหนะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "towards, in the direction of",
      "answer": "ข้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "five, the number or quantity five",
      "answer": "ห้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rohm↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "shade, sunshade, screen, blind, canopy, cover, covering, curtain, shield, veil",
      "answer": "ร่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[tham→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "morals and ethics, the good and decent principles of life",
      "answer": "ธรรม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cheuua↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to believe, to trust, to have faith in, to rely on",
      "answer": "เชื่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dooy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "by, via, the method, route, way or mode of attainment",
      "answer": "โดย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) crude, coarse, rough, rugged",
      "answer": "หยาบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "grandchild",
      "answer": "หลาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "power, force, strength, violence, military force",
      "answer": "พล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phruaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to break up into pieces, to loosen",
      "answer": "พรวน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raaek↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) first, primary, initial",
      "answer": "แรก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jit↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "the mind, mentality",
      "answer": "จิต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiiang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to contradict, to argue, to dispute, to talk back",
      "answer": "เถียง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaw↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to culture (germs), to cultivate, to plant, to build (body)",
      "answer": "เพาะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yaawm↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "can, naturally, as a matter of course, inevitably",
      "answer": "ย่อม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laawy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to float, to set afloat or adrift, to waft through (the air)",
      "answer": "ลอย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohm↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to deserve, to meet with",
      "answer": "สม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL gaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "type, kind, sort, species, variety, method, item",
      "answer": "ประการ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aehng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "by oneself, on one's own, personally, myself, oneself, himself, themselves",
      "answer": "เอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to collect (liquid) under (a spout)",
      "answer": "รอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaawn↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "lump, chunk, small rock, clump, ball, mass",
      "answer": "ก้อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) bad, evil, wicked",
      "answer": "ชั่ว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[guu↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to borrow (i.e. money) on interest",
      "answer": "กู้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "tail",
      "answer": "หาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL nai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "why, wherefore",
      "answer": "ไฉน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpeert↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to open, to turn on, engage",
      "answer": "เปิด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reerm↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to begin, to start, commence",
      "answer": "เริ่ม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[moongF maai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to aim at or for, to intend, to mean, to endeavor, to attempt",
      "answer": "มุ่งหมาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to bloom, open, blossom, unfold",
      "answer": "บาน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leeuy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(used for emphasis at the end of a statement) \"...at all.\" — \"...so much!\" — \"...extremely!, completely, directly, simply, without doing anything else first, right away",
      "answer": "เลย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaen→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to subsitute, represent, replace",
      "answer": "แทน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maawp↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to assign, entrust, turn over, commit, deliver",
      "answer": "มอบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haang↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) distant, far from, far away, far apart",
      "answer": "ห่าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "groove, conduit, rail, track",
      "answer": "ราง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ngiiap↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) quiet, peaceful, silent",
      "answer": "เงียบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaaw↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "also, too, as well, well..., (suggestion) should...",
      "answer": "ก็"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to admire, compliment, praise, commend, extol, flatter, pay tribute to, salute, speak highly of",
      "answer": "ชม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to lack, need",
      "answer": "ขาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sing↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general term for) a thing, item",
      "answer": "สิ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[gaawn↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "before, earlier, time gone by, prior to, in advance of, ahead of time, previously, formerly, initially, beforehand, firstly, now, ago",
      "answer": "ก่อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baaen→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) flat",
      "answer": "แบน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) missing a part, incomplete, fragmented",
      "answer": "ขาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khaa↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a journey or trip) trip, time",
      "answer": "ขา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpriiap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to compare, to contrast",
      "answer": "เปรียบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "name, designation, appellation",
      "answer": "นาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lakH saL na↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "characteristic, form, attribute, quality, pattern, style",
      "answer": "ลักษณะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaaw↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "duct, pipe, hose, tube",
      "answer": "ท่อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[san↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of length) (is) short, squat",
      "answer": "สั้น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jit↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "of the mind, mental",
      "answer": "จิต"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaL sohm↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to combine, mix",
      "answer": "ผสม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to build, construct, create, establish, to cause",
      "answer": "สร้าง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL jam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) assigned, permanently placed, constant, fixed",
      "answer": "ประจำ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[jaw↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to puncture, to bore, to pierce, to punch a hole, to perforate",
      "answer": "เจาะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL det↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(royal use only) to come or go, describing the movement of a Royal person",
      "answer": "เสด็จ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[roong↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "dawn, daybreak",
      "answer": "รุ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raH biiap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "order, regulations, system",
      "answer": "ระเบียบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to follow, along, around",
      "answer": "ตาม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaao↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(title for a king or god)",
      "answer": "ท้าว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phleerng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "fire, blaze, flame, conflagration",
      "answer": "เพลิง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[reuuang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "about, relating to, concerning, (as part of the header in an official letter along with เรียน ) \"Subject:\"",
      "answer": "เรื่อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) any",
      "answer": "ใด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[raawng↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cry out, to scream, to exclaim, to weep, to sob, to yell, to roar, to squeal",
      "answer": "ร้อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[johp↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to end, to finish",
      "answer": "จบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraawm↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "in unison, concurrently, at the same time, fully",
      "answer": "พร้อม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to train, practice, drill or exercise, make proficient, learn to",
      "answer": "หัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[euuaF feuua↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) considerate, helpful, generous, friendly",
      "answer": "เอื้อเฟื้อ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[leuuan↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to promote",
      "answer": "เลื่อน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[hat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "measles, rubseola, a highly contageous skin disease",
      "answer": "หัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaeng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to adorn, decorate, beautify",
      "answer": "แต่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laaen↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to move, to run, to sail, to glide, to slide, to steam",
      "answer": "แล่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[loom↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hole, hole in the ground, pit",
      "answer": "หลุม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaan↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to cross, pass, pass by, pass through, pass an exam",
      "answer": "ผ่าน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[luaang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) royal, of the court, superior, official, great",
      "answer": "หลวง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtohn→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "self, person, man, oneself",
      "answer": "ตน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) thin, weak, light, fine",
      "answer": "บาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruu↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to know a subject or piece of learned information",
      "answer": "รู้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[faak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to deposit, leave, entrust (something), consign",
      "answer": "ฝาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "rice farm, rice paddy, grain field",
      "answer": "นา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phraam→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Brahman, an ancient religion",
      "answer": "พราหมณ์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khloom→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) covered (over), hidden, unclear, enveloped, blanketed (with)",
      "answer": "คลุม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL miian↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "clerk, secretary",
      "answer": "เสมียน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL haai↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "friend, companion, pal",
      "answer": "สหาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[riiang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to arrange, place in order, line up",
      "answer": "เรียง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[naa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a prefix to a verb or adjective to indicate a persistent state or greater intensity of description) extremely, very, intensely, entrenched, really",
      "answer": "น่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to latch or fasten",
      "answer": "ขัด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[neung↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "one, the number or quantity one",
      "answer": "หนึ่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saL dtaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "\"sadang,\" a Thai coin worth one one-hundredth of a Baht, (figuratively meaning) money (in a general sense)",
      "answer": "สตางค์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maiM dtree→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "amicability, friendship, goodwill, (to be on) good terms",
      "answer": "ไมตรี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[loong→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "uncle, elder uncle, elder brother of a parent, great uncle",
      "answer": "ลุง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL gaawp↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to combine, to put together, to build, to assemble, to make, to erect",
      "answer": "ประกอบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaae↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "be defeated (by), to lose (to), to fail",
      "answer": "แพ้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yooH ro:hp↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(Thai transcription of the foreign loanword) Europe",
      "answer": "ยุโรป"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ling→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "monkey",
      "answer": "ลิง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phra↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a title or prefix word used with a most revered person, place, or object) royal",
      "answer": "พระ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "direction, way, path, course, the way",
      "answer": "ทาง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aaM haan↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "food, meal, diet",
      "answer": "อาหาร"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lae↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(a colloquial particle used to emphasize what precedes it)",
      "answer": "แหล่ะ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[yoht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to drip",
      "answer": "หยด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[baawk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to say, tell, inform, mention, state, relate, let (someone) know",
      "answer": "บอก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtaaek↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to break, burst, shatter, smash, break in pieces, break out, blossom",
      "answer": "แตก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuaak↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of people, animals) a group, a party",
      "answer": "พวก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thiiang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "12:00 h, 12 p.m., noon",
      "answer": "เที่ยง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "allowing that, if, despite, rather",
      "answer": "หาก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[witH thaH yaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "science, knowledge, learning, philosophy",
      "answer": "วิทยา"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khiaao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) green",
      "answer": "เขียว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheet↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "draw, scratch, write",
      "answer": "ขีด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtraL guun→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "family, lineage, pedigree, lineage",
      "answer": "ตระกูล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phra↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "priest, minister, cleric, monk, padre, god, Buddha image",
      "answer": "พระ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[saawng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to look in a mirror",
      "answer": "ส่อง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaH maa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "Burma, Burmese",
      "answer": "พม่า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thuun→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to place in an elevated position, to respect, to revere, to worship, to esteem",
      "answer": "ทูน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ruuH jak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a person, place, or idea) to know",
      "answer": "รู้จัก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "thousand, the number one thousand (1,000)",
      "answer": "พัน"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chen↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "such as, for example, for instance, like, e.g.",
      "answer": "เช่น"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ro:hk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "disease, sickness, case",
      "answer": "โรค"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpraL phreut↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to behave, to conduct oneself, to act, to perform or do",
      "answer": "ประพฤติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[niu↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "finger, toe, digit",
      "answer": "นิ้ว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ratH thaL baan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "government",
      "answer": "รัฐบาล"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "an animal, animals",
      "answer": "สัตว์"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[thaH wee→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to multiply, increase, add, double",
      "answer": "ทวี"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[khoht↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) coiled, curled up, rolled up, twisted or bent into a coil",
      "answer": "ขด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bplaap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) thrilling, flashing, shining",
      "answer": "ปลาบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[meeM naaM khohm→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "March",
      "answer": "ปมีนาคม"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaL bap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "transcript, document, copy",
      "answer": "ฉบับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpohkL khraawng→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to rule, administer, govern",
      "answer": "กครอง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[graL suaang→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "ministry",
      "answer": "กระทรวง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[maH let↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "seed, grain, tiny piece, bean",
      "answer": "เมล็ด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sohng↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to ship, send or deliver (mail or parcel or package),guayR dtiaaoR emit",
      "answer": "ส่ง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[rap↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to receive, get, accept, catch a thrown object, take, to fetch, to pick (someone) up, (colloq.) telephone call",
      "answer": "รับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dteuk↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "building, brickwork, a brick structure",
      "answer": "ตึก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aa→ khaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "building",
      "answer": "อาคาร"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไม่มีวัน",
      "question": "never (in the future)"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[kheeuy→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(have you) ever, (as) before, did in the past, used to...",
      "answer": "เคย"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ไม่เคย",
      "question": "never (in the past)"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[guay↗ dtiaao↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "rice noodles",
      "answer": "ก๋วยเตี๋ยว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dta↓ giiap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "chopsticks",
      "answer": "ตะเกียบ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[laawt↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "drinking straw",
      "answer": "หลอด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaa↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "cloth, material, fabric",
      "answer": "ผ้า"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chet↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to wipe, to rub, to scrub",
      "answer": "เช็ด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[dtuaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(of a person) self, himself, herself, yourself, themselves, (things) itself",
      "answer": "ตัว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phaa↘ chet↑ dtuaa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "towel",
      "answer": "ผ้าเช็ดตัว"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sa↓ aat↓] (adj or verb)"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to clean",
      "answer": "สะอาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sa↓ baai→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) happy, comfortable, fine",
      "answer": "สบาย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[sa↓ duaak↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(is) convenient, comfortable",
      "answer": "สะดวก"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chai↑]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to use, to employ or exploit an object, to utilize, to resort to, to implement",
      "answer": "ใช้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[waeh→ laa→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "(general) time (as in space and time)",
      "answer": "เวลา"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ใช้เวลา",
      "question": "spend time"
    },
    {
      "answer": "วันเกิด",
      "question": "birthday"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[cha↓ laawng↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "celebrate",
      "answer": "ฉลอง"
    },
    {
      "answer": "ฉลองวันเกิด",
      "question": "celebrate birthday"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[lang↗]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "behind, following, at the rear",
      "answer": "หลัง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[glap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to return or go back",
      "answer": "กลับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "period of time",
      "answer": "ช่วง"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chuaang↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "this period of time",
      "answer": "ช่วงนี้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ro:hk↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "disease, sickness, case",
      "answer": "โรค"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ra↑ dap↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "level, grade",
      "answer": "ระดับ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "level 2",
      "answer": "ระดับที่2"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[chaat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "national",
      "answer": "ชาติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ra↑ dap↓ chaat↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "national level",
      "answer": "ระดับชาติ"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phrae↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to publicize, broadcast, make public, disseminate",
      "answer": "แพร่"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[ra↑ baat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "to break out (war or disease)",
      "answer": "ระบาด"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phrae↘ ra↑ baat↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "epidemic",
      "answer": "แพร่ระบาด"
    },
    {
      "answer": "การระบาดของโรค",
      "question": "spread of a disease"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[aa→ gaan→]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "symptoms",
      "answer": "อาการ"
    },
    {
      "answer": "อาการของโรค",
      "question": "symptoms of the disease"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuu↘]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "person, human, case",
      "answer": "ผู้"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[bpuay↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "is sick",
      "answer": "ป่วย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[phuu↘ bpuay↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "patient, the sick",
      "answer": "ผู้ป่วย"
    },
    {
      "details": [
        {
          "description": "[haaw↗ phuu↘ bpuay↓]"
        }
      ],
      "question": "hospital ward",
      "answer": "หอผู้ป่วย"
    }
  ],
  "subject": "Thai_language",
  "type": "BUTTON",
  "sentence": null,
  "voice_2": null,
  "number": "1"
}
